A Guide to the Edgar R. Hon Collection on Tysons Corner Silver Line Metro Development, 2003-2006
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Edgar R. Hon Collection on Tysons Corner Silver Line Metro Development, 2003-2006
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-53
0.5 linear feet
The Edgar R. Hon Collection on Tysons Corner Silver Line Metro Development consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 2003-2006 consisting of Hon’s assemblage of photocopied newspaper text, photographic imagery, drawings, and personal notes about the proposed redevelopment of Tysons Corner and the Metrorail’s Silver Line.
Hon, Edgar R. (1931-2007)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Edgar R. Hon throughout 2003-2006
Historical and Biographical Information
Edgar Rodman Hon was born in Washington, D.C. on September 28, 1931 to Stella and Edgar E. Hon. He grew up in Hyattsville and Bladensburg, Maryland and went on to attend the University of Maryland and Columbia Technical Institute, Washington, D.C. Hon later completed survey training at the Engineer School in Fort Belvoir, Virginia, and was assigned to the Eighth United States Army topographic engineer company in Korea. In 1953-1954, Hon worked on field surveys to update maps with the newly established Demilitarized Zone separating North and South Korea.
Upon discharge from the Army, Hon joined the staff of Georgetown University’s Graduate School. In 1963, he worked as a cartographer for the Federal government undertaking field surveys for the National Map Division, U.S. Geological Survey, and Department of the Interior. Hon retired as a cartographer in 1984.
Hon moved to McLean, Virginia in 1975, and lived in the Commons of McLean until his death. An avid fan of history, he wrote articles for historical societies in Arkansas, Fairfax County, and Fairfax County Public Library’s Virginia Room. Hon also wrote short fiction stories for Storyteller Magazine. From 2003-2006, Hon collected and compiled news stories and documented the Tyson’s Corner Redevelopment and Silver Line Metro Rail construction. He died at age 76 on November 15, 2007 in McLean, Virginia and is buried in Baltimore National Cemetery.
Scope and Content
The Edgar R. Hon Collection on Tysons Corner Silver Line Metro Development consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 2003-2006 consisting of Hon’s assemblage of photocopied newspaper text, photographic imagery, drawings, and personal notes about the proposed redevelopment of Tysons Corner and the Metrorail’s Silver Line. Hon photographed areas around the proposed “Tysons East” Metro Station, which is today known as the McLean Metro Station. Photos included are of the Commons of McLean apartments, Commons Shopping Village, Wilson Building (7600 Old Springhouse Road), Washington Building (7998 Old Springhouse Road), Capital One office complex, Gate of McLean Condominiums, Mitre Plaza, and other nearby scenes along Route 123/Dolley Madison Boulevard.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project; Hon, Edgar R. (1931-2007); Land use - Virginia - Fairfax County; Local transit - Virginia - Fairfax County; McLean (Va.); Subways -Virginia - Fairfax County; Tysons Corner (Va.)
Container List
- The Commons of McLean Apartments, and the Proposed “Tysons East” Railway Station Site: History Past and Present, 2003
- Metrorail’s Silver Line: News of Progress, and Views of Demolition Vicinity of “Tysons East,” Late 2003 to Mid-July 2004, 2003-2004
- Photos and negatives of area surrounding proposed “Tysons East” Station [35 mm negatives], 2003 August-2004 July
- The Commons of McLean Apartments: A Collection of Memorabilia, 2004 November
- Developments, Metrorail and Vicinity of “Tysons East” Station Site, 2nd Half of 2004, 2004
- News of Metrorail, January-May 2005, 2004-2005
- News, Extension of Metrorail, Dulles Corridor, late May-September 2005, 2005
- News, Extension of Metrorail, Dulles Corridor, October-December 2005, 2005
- The Silver Line and Tysons Corner, January-March 2006, 2006
- The Silver Line and Tysons Corner, April-May 2006, 2006
- The Silver Line and Tysons Corner, June-July 2006, 2006
- The Silver Line and Tysons Corner, August-September 2006, 2006
- The Silver Line and Tysons Corner, October-December 2006, 2006